<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Dan Schlosser</title><link>http://danrs.ch/</link><description>The latest blog posts, updates, and other news from Dan Schlosser.</description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 12:47:57 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>PyRSS2Gen-1.1.0</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>A "Hello World" of sorts</title><link>http://danrs.ch/blog/post-2013-05-04.html</link><description>

How exciting, finally after over a year of rumination and weeks of development, danrs.ch is finally live!  This site has been in the pipeline for a while, and I certainly have some lofty goals for it in the future.  On this blog page, I will share my most recent thoughts and projects. I plan to post about technology, music, culture, or whatever else is affecting my life in the moment.

As my website reaches launch, I want to take this opportunity to thank Alex Akers, an iOS developer and friend who was extremely helpful in getting everything up and running.

If you have thoughts or comments that you would like to share, please send me an email at dan@danrs.ch, I'd love to hear from you! Hello, World!

</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://danrs.ch/blog/post-2013-05-04.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2013 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Updates: RSS and Blog Features</title><link>http://danrs.ch/blog/post-2013-05-09.html</link><description>

I've just updated the site with a few new features!  I now have an RSS Feed, where you can subscribe to my blog posts! In addition, I have also added blog post preview to the blog roll, so that longer posts don't take up the whole screen.  Plus, there's a nifty animation transitioning from the blog into a post and back!  Click the "see-more" button to try it out, and be sure to let me know what you think!

This update is in anticipation of longer blog posts to come, and my blog infrastructure (much of which I'm writing myself), needs improvement.  The system I use is a little complicated, but sort of cool.  I first write my blog posts in Markdown using MarkdownPad.  I save my finished posts to an HTML file on my server.  Then, when I commit my update to the live site, a git pre-commit hook updates the list of blog posts that my site has access to, and runs a Python script that generates my RSS Feed.  It's a little wonky.

Browser back and forward buttons are currently unsupported by my website, which is a bummer, and right now while I can link to blog posts, that displayed URL gets changed to the default danrs.ch/#blog.  This means that URL sharing is hard, and if you refresh, you see the blog roll as opposed to the full post.  Further updates will probably involve introducing new URLs for each page to fix this.

</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://danrs.ch/blog/post-2013-05-09.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>I'm on Flickr!</title><link>http://danrs.ch/blog/post-2013-06-29.html</link><description>

In a bold step towards getting into photography, I bought the Sony Alpha NEX-6, a mirrorless interchangeable lens camera with the kit 16-55mm lens.  Although I'm an absolute novice photographer, I'm trying to take myself seriously, and have committed to uploading my photos to my Flickr account. In an age of Dropbox and Google+ instant photo upload, I wasn't convinced that I would need a dedicated service for my photos.  My Galaxy Nexus uploads every food pic and selfie without being asked, which is great, but both Google+ and Dropbox have their disadvantages when handling pictures taken with a proper camera.

Google+ is fine for smartphone photos, but any pictures larger than 2048 x 2048 start to 
take up valuable Google Drive storage. 
For Dropbox, even my 21GB of free storage will go fast with 16.1MP (4912 x 3264) photos from my camera.  Because I'm cheep, and Flickr recently upgraded their free accounts to include a whopping 1TB of storage, I've decided to upload photos there.

After having used Flickr for over a month now, I can definitely say that I'm impressed. It's great for my basic uploading and grouping needs, and the photostream view is really nice to showcase my latest photos.  The NEX-6 is extremely portable and takes surprisingly beautiful photos, and it's nice to be able to throw my SD card into my laptop and have a batch of photos uploaded to my stream in under and hour.

Flickr is far from perfect though. It lacks the ability to download photos en mass, and sharing photos to social networks is a little finicky.  It's easy to share one photo or an entire set, but there isn't an easy way to share the best three photos, for example.  The NEX-6 can beam photos to my phone over Wi-Fi Direct, which sort of solves this problem, but it would be nice to be able to post multiple photos from my computer as well.

Posting to Flickr feels a little weird still, most because it's fairly disconnected from the rest of the Internet. (Who really goes and checks for updates on someone's Flickr feed?)  Unless Facebook or Google+ were able to pull in all of my Flickr photos automatically, there really isn't a great solution to these problems.  I certainly glad I moved to Flickr though, there's nothing worse than the feeling that Facebook is the only place where I store my photos online. If I want the perfect free photo-upload service, I'll have to write it myself, I guess.  Big surprise.

</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://danrs.ch/blog/post-2013-06-29.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>I like Macs and Hate Myself</title><link>http://danrs.ch/blog/post-2013-07-16.html</link><description>

Hello, my name is Dan and I am an Apple hater.

Most people that know me know that I can't stand Apple.  I don't like Apple's culture, the price tags on their products, or their design principles.  I think the iPod is dead, the iPhone is still a product of 2007, and the iPad needs a few more hours in the proverbial oven.  I could rant for hours about how Apple doesn't understand the Internet, or how they've "screwed up this" or "forgotten about that."  I am not unfounded in my dislike for Apple, either; I am not just a techno-hipster that's "too cool for school," if people still say that.   From my perspective, it seems apparent that Apple is on course to make some extremely serious mistakes in the next 10-15 years and that if they do so they will be the Blackberry or the Palm of 2030.

But that's not why I'm writing this.

I'm writing this because I've been working as an intern at Facebook for the past few weeks, writing code for upwards of nine hours a day on a 15-inch MacBook Pro with Retina Display.  I've had extensive, continuous exposure to OS X, not that I was given any choice in the matter. I've been developing for iOS, and this can only be done on a Mac. (Thanks, Apple.) I've been using OS X on school iMacs and friends' MacBooks for ages, but something was different this time, and I couldn't pin down what.

When people ask me why I dislike OS X so much, I always found it easiest to point to it's collection of bundled software.  The only worthwhile app included on a Mac is Terminal; the rest are utter garbage.  Safari, iTunes, iPhoto, the App Store, Mail, Calendar, Contacts etc. can all be scrapped, in my opinion.  Naturally, when I started using my work laptop, I installed Chome, SublimeText, Mou, and so on. After all that customization was done, I slowly found myself growing more accustomed to the experience.  I found myself growing more… fond of the experience.

Hello my name is Dan and my next laptop will be a Mac.

On the technical end, switching to a Mac is tempting. Programming on a *nix-based machine is a must.  It will be great to be able to copy bash commands directly into Terminal instead of translating them into MS-DOS first. Moreover, unless I decide to work at Microsoft my career as a software engineer will be spent on a Mac.  I've toyed with switching to Linux, but that really just replaces one set of problems with another.  Linux is great for programming and a bummer from a UI/UX perspective.  Software support is lacking for Linux as well, which is all the more reason to avoid it.  It's true, you can do anything with Linux that you can with OS X, it's just a matter of how hard you have to work to get it done and how you feel about looking at some variation of Terminal all day.

Also, OS X has a much more active developer community for non-gaming, non-enterprise software.  I can disable Dashboard, Launchpad, and the dock, and replace them with Alfred, MagicPrefs, and Cinch. Under all the iClutter, there's a quite usable operating system &amp;mdash; and that's what is so surprising.  I've always faulted Macs for their software, but now it seems my criticisms have grown increasingly invalid. As a side note, I really enjoy using Spaces, and while I did have some multi-monitor issues on Mountain Lion, apparently Mavericks fixes them.

The hardware on MacBooks is undeniably excellent.  The retina display is gorgeous, the trackpad is amazing, they have all the necessary ports (minus Ethernet, alas), and they run on top-of-the-line components. My problem with Mac hardware is actually more in finding a balance for features and portability.  The screen size and resolution on the 13" laptops are both too small across the board (even for the 13" MacBook Pro with Retina Display, which has an effective resolution of 1280 x 800). The 15" MacBook Pro with Retina Display, while powerful, is noticeably heavier than my Lenovo Thinkpad X1 Carbon. Running a 13" MacBook Pro with Retina Display at 1650 x 1050 is a decent option, but reviews have indicated that the 13" model is underpowered, and I prefer full HD anyway.

Obviously, if I am looking for a way to drop $2500 on a computer the choice is clear, but it's hard to stomach spending all that money if I'm not going to be using 90% of the included software. This is especially true looking forward; it's hard to ask me to spend a lot of money on a traditional laptop when there are some really enticing touch-enabled ultrabooks out there.

Confusions / Conclusions

There are so many problems with getting a Mac, and arguably just as many sitting with Windows.  Windows 8 is built on a strong core, but can be aggravating.  I don't exactly have problems with Windows 8, it's just not satisfying to usefor a nerd like me.  Behind the flashy Start Screen trash Windows 8 is a clean, fast operating system.  The same goes for OS X.  It's hard to justify buying a Mac just to put other software on it, but I realized that OS X now has both the ecosystem and hardware advantage over Windows, a recent shift to be sure.  A MacBook will never run PC games, which is why I have (and always will have) a Windows desktop.  The truth is that by continuing to use a Windows laptop, I'm only delaying the inevitable.  For programming, for design work, for running a website, and for general compatibility, OS X is where I'm headed.

It pains me to think about carrying around a MacBook as my personal laptop. It's so much easier to complain about Apple as a company when I don't own any of their products, but I'm trapped.  I am going to have to learn to balance my moral opposition for Apple with the practicalities of life.  It may sound like I'm taking myself too seriously but it's true.  I'm going be on OS X sooner or later, so there's no reason not to switch now.  Especially with a new batch of Haswell-equipped MacBook Pros launching sometime this year, the hardware is increasingly enticing.  The question isn't if I'm going to buy a Mac, it's whether or not I'll be able to live with myself when I do.

</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://danrs.ch/blog/post-2013-07-16.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pebble Smartwatch, Artificial Beef, and Windows 8.1: Why We Need More Betas</title><link>http://danrs.ch/blog/post-2013-08-18.html</link><description>

I got a Pebble this week.  (Not a rock, of course, I bought the Pebble Smartwatch: smartphone companion and Kickstarter sensation.)  I pre-ordered my Pebble six months ago after reading about what was and since has become the first practical smartwatch in existence.  It's chassis is attractive, and the e-paper display allows for excellent battery life.  It is packed full of sensors and meters, and still manages to be waterproof. Despite all this, the Pebble is ultimately a flawed product, and I knew this when I bought it. In fact, the Pebble's flaws were actually a large part of why I preordered it in the first place.

The Pebble is currently the most popular consumer smartwatch in the market, but this may not be the case for long.  Google, Apple, Samsung, and others are all rumored to be developing smartwatches to be released later this year and into 2014.  The problem with these rumored smartwatches is that they will inevitably be sold as consumer products, rather than development devices. The difference with Pebble is that while neither it nor its soon-to-be-announced competitors will be a perfect implementation of a smartwatch, only Pebble will be open-source, meaning that I can install the Pebble SDK and start developing for it myself.  Purchasers of the Pebble have the distinct opportunity to be a part of defining the smartwatch market, and that is what is worth paying for.

If the Pebble is viewed as a consumer product it does not hold up to expectations.  Notifications are not actionable, it is fairly useless without a companion smartphone, and its app ecosystem is small.  Whether the folks over at Team Pebble are saying it explicitly or not, their product is in beta.  I expect that those that want a Pebble just for personal use will be disappointed, and will probably be better off waiting a year or two for the market to mature.  The Pebble is best fitted for eager developers like me, and while it may be years until the smartwatch market is out of beta, the developer community will continue to support and drive innovation in the market.

While I was tracking my Pebble shipment this week, I was also tracking a news story about the researchers who developed the world's first lab-grown burger, which is, in it's own way, a beta.  There are a lot of cool things about a future without factory farms, and this development could mean a radical shift in the meat production industry, quite likely for the better.  On the other hand, there are significant unexplored medical concerns with eating food grown in labs, and so until these issues are addressed, cultured beef will remain a laboratory product.  There isn't any way that these hamburgers could be put on supermarket shelves today, but that doesn't mean they won't sometime in the future.  The lab-grown hamburger is a proof of concept, meant to stir up discussion and interest about this topic, and it appears to have been successful.  I would wager that the FDA won't be approving this or any other "food beta" in the next year or two, but maybe if projects like these continue a healthier, cheaper, and more ecological meat product will be widely available in super-markets and restaurants.

Betas are important.  At the most basic level, a beta represents a connection between developers and consumers.  Beyond the basic exchange of bug reports and feature suggestions, participation in a beta has symbolic meaning for both parties.  By putting their products in beta a company says "We care about your input," and by participating a beta tester says "I care about your product mission, I want you to keep working on this."  Beta testers are doing a very important job, both improving the product and staying the complaints of those that would have a project cancelled just because it isn't finished.  Betas are about what the product will look like, not what it looks like now.  Product mission is the reason why I have a Pebble on my wrist, and why I am running Windows 8.1 Preview on my laptop.  With Windows 8, Microsoft set out to design an intuitive and touch-friendly user interface that maintains the functionality of traditional Windows.  I am the first to admit that Windows 8.1 (and by extension Windows 8) doesn't deliver fully on this goal, but I want Microsoft to know that their work is important to me.

I don't think that everyone should start buying beta products, and I don't think that every product should be beta-tested.  As a developer of products (of any kind, I would argue), it is important to consider whether or not you really know better than your customers what your product should look like.  The Pebble is most importantly a smartwatch platform for third-party development, just as the lab burger is most-importantly a conversation starter.  These products are not final and are not perfect, which is why living off of betas can be painful. (If you don't believe me, ask anyone with iOS 7 on their phone.)  The traditional product release model is too much of a guessing game.  Years of R&amp;amp;D lead up to a product launch that has the development team crossing their proverbial fingers.  This is no bargain. Product design should be collaborative.  We need more betas.

</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://danrs.ch/blog/post-2013-08-18.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2013 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>