<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Dan Schlosser</title><link>http://danrs.ch/</link><description>The latest blog posts, updates, and other news from Dan Schlosser.</description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 22:12:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>PyRSS2Gen-1.1.0</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>A "Hello World" of sorts</title><link>http://danrs.ch/blog/post-2013-05-04</link><description>

How exciting, finally after over a year of rumination and weeks of development, danrs.ch is finally live!  This site has been in the pipeline for a while, and I certainly have some lofty goals for it in the future.  On this blog page, I will share my most recent thoughts and projects. I plan to post about technology, music, culture, or whatever else is affecting my life in the moment.

As my website reaches launch, I want to take this opportunity to thank Alex Akers, an iOS developer and friend who was extremely helpful in getting everything up and running.

If you have thoughts or comments that you would like to share, please send me an email at dan@danrs.ch, I'd love to hear from you! Hello, World!

</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://danrs.ch/blog/post-2013-05-04</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2013 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Updates: RSS and Blog Features</title><link>http://danrs.ch/blog/post-2013-05-09</link><description>tes: RSS and Blog Features

May 9, 2013

I've just updated the site with a few new features!  I now have an RSS Feed, where you can subscribe to my blog posts! In addition, I have also added blog post preview to the blog roll, so that longer posts don't take up the whole screen.  Plus, there's a nifty animation transitioning from the blog into a post and back!  Click the "see-more" button to try it out, and be sure to let me know what you think!

This update is in anticipation of longer blog posts to come, and my blog infrastructure (much of which I'm writing myself), needs improvement.  The system I use is a little complicated, but sort of cool.  I first write my blog posts in Markdown using MarkdownPad.  I save my finished posts to an HTML file on my server.  Then, when I commit my update to the live site, a git pre-commit hook updates the list of blog posts that my site has access to, and runs a Python script that generates my RSS Feed.  It's a little wonky.

Browser back and forward buttons are currently unsupported by my website, which is a bummer, and right now while I can link to blog posts, that displayed URL gets changed to the default danrs.ch/#blog.  This means that URL sharing is hard, and if you refresh, you see the blog roll as opposed to the full post.  Further updates will probably involve introducing new URLs for each page to fix this.

</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://danrs.ch/blog/post-2013-05-09</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>